Mss.Rec.125 Mss.Rec.125
American Philosophical Society
Onondaga text and translation of the Gibson-Goldenweiser text of the Deganawidah epic
1969-1971
Mss.Rec.125
American Philosophical Society
31.0 Tape(s)
A reading and translation of the Onondaga text of the Deganawidah epic as given in 1912 by Chief John A. Gibson and transcribed by Alexander Goldenweiser. The tapes alternate between two types: the re-reading of short segments of the text by William Fenton, which are then repeated in correct pronunciation by the native consultants; the replaying in short sections of these first tapes with translations and English glosses provided by the consultants. Howard Sky is the consultant on tapes 1-23, with his nephew James Sky taking over on tapes 24-31. Includes occasional additional commentary in English.
31 sound tape reels (92 hr., 19 min.): analog, 1 7/8 ips, half track, mono; 5 in.
Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912
Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940
Sky, Howard
Sky, James
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Presented by William N. Fenton, August 16, 1985.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Tapes 1-23 contain an intermittent, uncorrectable background hum.
Related Archival Materials
A version of the text used in the recording as well as additional related materials are available in the William N. Fenton Papers (Mss.Ms.Coll.20)
Deganawida; Iroquois Indians--Folklore; Iroquois Indians--History; Onondaga language; Sound recordings
- Audio recordings
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga text, beginning through page 32, 1969-01-22; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:07; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
    Scope and Contents note
    A reading of the Onondaga text of the Deganawidah epic as given in 1912 by Chief John A. Gibson and transcribed by Alexander Goldenweiser. This program consists of the re-reading of short segments of the text by William Fenton, which are then repeated in correct pronunciation by Howard Sky. Includes occasional discussion in English. Fenton's voice on the program is occasionally faint or inaudible. There is a persistent background hum that has been partially corrected.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Sound tape reel) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Anthropological linguistics; Brantford (Ont.); Deganawida; Iroquois Indians--History; Onondaga language--Texts
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga text, page 32 to 55, 1969-01-22; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:34:59; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 22 to 32, 1969-01-22; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:34:44; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
    A translation of the Onondaga text of the Deganawidah epic as given in 1912 by Chief John A. Gibson and transcribed by Alexander Goldenweiser. This program alternates frequently between two forms of interaction. The first is the re-playing of previously recorded readings of short segments of the Onondaga text by William Fenton and Howard Sky, which is followed by the re-reading of the Onondaga text by Fenton, with English translation given by Howard Sky. Includes occasional discussion in English. There is a persistent background hum that has been partially corrected. Sound levels frequently and suddenly fluctuate throughout the recording. Fenton's voice on the program is occasionally faint or inaudible.
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 32 to 41, 1969-01-22; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:53; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 41 to 47, 1969-04-03; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:46:00; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 47 to 55, 1969-04-03; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:15; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga text, page 55 to 79, 1969-04-10; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:43; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga text, page 79 to 107, 1969-04-10; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:39; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 55 to 73 [1 of 2], 1969-04; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:34; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
    A translation of the Onondaga text of the Deganawidah epic as given in 1912 by Chief John A. Gibson and transcribed by Alexander Goldenweiser. This program alternates frequently between two forms of interaction. The first is the re-playing of previously recorded readings of short segments of the Onondaga text by William Fenton and Howard Sky, which is followed by the re-reading of the Onondaga text by Fenton, with English translation given by Howard Sky. Includes occasional discussion in English. There is a persistent background hum that has been partially corrected. Sound levels periodically fluctuate throughout the recording. Fenton's voice on the program is occasionally faint or inaudible.
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 55 to 73 [2 of 2], 1969-04; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:42; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 73 to 84, 1969-04-14; 06-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:37:10; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 84 to 94, 1969-04-14; 06-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:37:54; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 94 to 105, 1969-04-16; 07-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:33; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 105 to 114, 1969-04-17; 07-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:36; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
    A translation of the Onondaga text of the Deganawidah epic as given in 1912 by Chief John A. Gibson and transcribed by Alexander Goldenweiser. This program alternates frequently between two forms of interaction. The first is the re-playing of previously recorded readings of short segments of the Onondaga text by William Fenton and Howard Sky, which is followed by the re-reading of the Onondaga text by Fenton, with English translation given by Howard Sky. Includes occasional discussion in English. There is a persistent uncorrected background hum throughout the recording. Sound levels frequently and suddenly fluctuate throughout the recording. Fenton's voice on the program is occasionally faint or inaudible.
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga text, page 107 to 134, 1969-04-15; 08-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:39; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
    A reading of the Onondaga text of the Deganawidah epic as given in 1912 by Chief John A. Gibson and transcribed by Alexander Goldenweiser. This program consists of the re-reading of short segments of the text by William Fenton, which are then repeated in correct pronunciation by Howard Sky. Includes occasional discussion in English. There is a persistent uncorrected background hum throughout the recording.
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga text, page 134 to 140, 1969-04-15; 08-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:21; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
    A reading of the Onondaga text of the Deganawidah epic as given in 1912 by Chief John A. Gibson and transcribed by Alexander Goldenweiser. This program consists of the re-reading of short segments of the text by William Fenton, which are then repeated in correct pronunciation by Howard Sky. Includes occasional discussion in English. There is a persistent background hum that has been partially corrected. Sound levels frequently and suddenly fluctuate throughout the recording. Fenton's voice on the program is occasionally faint or inaudible.
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 115 to 125, 1969-04-17; 09-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:15; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 125 to 136, 1969-04-20; 09-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:07; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 136 to 145, 1969-04-20; 10-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:45; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 146 to 153, 1969-06-10; 10-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:37:06; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 153 to 163, 1969-06-11; 11-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:37:59; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 163 to 169, 1969-06-11; 11-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:52:39; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 169 to 177, 1969-06-12; 11-03; 1.0 .mp3; 01:30:27; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
    A translation of the Onondaga text of the Deganawidah epic as given in 1912 by Chief John A. Gibson and transcribed by Alexander Goldenweiser. This program alternates frequently between two forms of interaction. The first is the re-playing of previously recorded readings of short segments of the Onondaga text by William Fenton and Howard Sky, which is followed by the re-reading of the Onondaga text by Fenton, with English translation given by Howard Sky. Includes occasional discussion in English. There is a persistent background hum that has been partially corrected. Some sound distortion caused by digital speed correction. Sound levels frequently and suddenly fluctuate throughout the recording. Fenton's voice on the program is occasionally faint or inaudible.
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga text, page 160 to 190, 1969-06-11; 12-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:03:11; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
    A reading of the Onondaga text of the Deganawidah epic as given in 1912 by Chief John A. Gibson and transcribed by Alexander Goldenweiser. This program consists of the re-reading of short segments of the text by William Fenton, which are then repeated in correct pronunciation by Howard Sky. Includes occasional discussion in English. Fenton's voice on the program is occasionally faint or inaudible.
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga text, page 190 to 221, 1969-06-11; 12-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:03:19; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 177 to 187, 1969-06-13; 13-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:41; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 187 to 200, 1969-06-13; 13-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:22:06; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Transcription of notes regarding site of old Onondaga long house at Middleport, 1969-06-15; 13-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:14:28; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
    Brant (Ont.: County)--History; Brantford (Ont.); Longhouses; Onondaga Indians--History
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 201 to 207, 1969-06-16; 14-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:42; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 207 to 217, 1969-06-16; 14-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:35:25; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 217 to 229, 1969-06-16; 15-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:34:49; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
    A translation of the Onondaga text of the Deganawidah epic as given in 1912 by Chief John A. Gibson and transcribed by Alexander Goldenweiser. This program alternates frequently between two forms of interaction. The first is the re-playing of previously recorded readings of short segments of the Onondaga text by William Fenton and Howard Sky, which is followed by the re-reading of the Onondaga text by Fenton, with English translation given by Howard Sky. Includes occasional discussion in English. There is a persistent uncorrected background hum throughout the recording. Sound levels frequently and suddenly fluctuate throughout the recording. Fenton's voice on the program is occasionally faint or inaudible. 1:19 of silence deleted at 1:20:20.
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 229 to 240, 1969-06-16; 15-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:27:46; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
    A translation of the Onondaga text of the Deganawidah epic as given in 1912 by Chief John A. Gibson and transcribed by Alexander Goldenweiser. This program alternates frequently between two forms of interaction. The first is the re-playing of previously recorded readings of short segments of the Onondaga text by William Fenton and Howard Sky, which is followed by the re-reading of the Onondaga text by Fenton, with English translation given by Howard Sky. Includes occasional discussion in English. There is a persistent uncorrected background hum throughout the recording. Sound levels frequently and suddenly fluctuate throughout the recording. Fenton's voice on the program is occasionally faint or inaudible. 8:38 of silence deleted at 26:58.
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga text, page 221 to 240, 1969-06-17; 16-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:28; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga text, page 240 to 270, 1969-06-17; 16-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:44:46; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 240 to 249, 1969-06-19; 17-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:37:03; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 249 to 259, 1969-06-19; 17-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:33:33; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
    A translation of the Onondaga text of the Deganawidah epic as given in 1912 by Chief John A. Gibson and transcribed by Alexander Goldenweiser. This program alternates frequently between two forms of interaction. The first is the re-playing of previously recorded readings of short segments of the Onondaga text by William Fenton and Howard Sky, which is followed by the re-reading of the Onondaga text by Fenton, with English translation given by Howard Sky. Includes occasional discussion in English. There is a persistent uncorrected background hum throughout the recording. Sound levels frequently and suddenly fluctuate throughout the recording. Fenton's voice on the program is occasionally faint or inaudible. 1:43 of silence deleted at 14:37.
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 259 to 270, 1969-06-19; 18-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:04; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 271 to 279, 1970-06-23; 18-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:35:37; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
    A translation of the Onondaga text of the Deganawidah epic as given in 1912 by Chief John A. Gibson and transcribed by Alexander Goldenweiser. This program alternates frequently between two forms of interaction. The first is the re-playing of previously recorded readings of short segments of the Onondaga text by William Fenton and Howard Sky, which is followed by the re-reading of the Onondaga text by Fenton, with English translation given by Howard Sky. Includes occasional discussion in English. Sound levels frequently and suddenly fluctuate throughout the recording.
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga text, page 271 to 298, 1970-06-23; 19-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:27; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
    A reading of the Onondaga text of the Deganawidah epic as given in 1912 by Chief John A. Gibson and transcribed by Alexander Goldenweiser. This program consists of the re-reading of short segments of the text by William Fenton, which are then repeated in correct pronunciation by Howard Sky. Includes occasional discussion in English.
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga text, page 298 to 331, 1970-06-26; 19-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:32; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 279 to 289, 1970-06; 20-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:42; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
    A translation of the Onondaga text of the Deganawidah epic as given in 1912 by Chief John A. Gibson and transcribed by Alexander Goldenweiser. This program alternates frequently between two forms of interaction. The first is the re-playing of previously recorded readings of short segments of the Onondaga text by William Fenton and Howard Sky, which is followed by the re-reading of the Onondaga text by Fenton, with English translation given by Howard Sky. Includes occasional discussion in English.
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 289 to 300, 1970-06; 20-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:43; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 300 to 312, 1970-06-27; 21-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:24; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 312 to 325, 1970-06-27; 21-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:02; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 325 to 338, 1970-06-29; 22-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:37:05; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 338 to 359, 1970-06-29; 22-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:11:14; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
    A translation of the Onondaga text of the Deganawidah epic as given in 1912 by Chief John A. Gibson and transcribed by Alexander Goldenweiser. This program alternates frequently between two forms of interaction. The first is the re-playing of previously recorded readings of short segments of the Onondaga text by William Fenton and Howard Sky, which is followed by the re-reading of the Onondaga text by Fenton, with English translation given by Howard Sky. Includes occasional discussion in English. Pages 339-341 of the original text are missing from the recording at 8:04, with additional details given by Fenton.
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga text, page 331 to 359, 1970-06-29; 23-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:48:19; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Sky, Howard
    A reading of the Onondaga text of the Deganawidah epic as given in 1912 by Chief John A. Gibson and transcribed by Alexander Goldenweiser. This program consists of the re-reading of short segments of the text by William Fenton, which are then repeated in correct pronunciation by Howard Sky. Includes occasional discussion in English. At the beginning of the recording, the tape number is misidentified by Fenton as tape 22. It is actually tape 23. Sound levels periodically fluctuate throughout the recording.
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga text, page 360 to 387, 1971-05-15; 24-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:34:13; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Skye, James
    A reading of the Onondaga text of the Deganawidah epic as given in 1912 by Chief John A. Gibson and transcribed by Alexander Goldenweiser. This program consists of the re-reading of short segments of the text by William Fenton, which are then repeated in correct pronunciation by James Skye. Includes occasional discussion in English.
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 360 to 365, 1971-05-15; 25-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:35; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Skye, James
    A translation of the Onondaga text of the Deganawidah epic as given in 1912 by Chief John A. Gibson and transcribed by Alexander Goldenweiser. This program alternates frequently between two forms of interaction. The first is the re-playing of previously recorded readings of short segments of the Onondaga text by William Fenton and Howard Sky, which is followed by the re-reading of the Onondaga text by Fenton, with English translation given by James Skye. Includes occasional discussion in English.
  - Concerning the League: Onondaga to English, page 365 to 372, 1971-05-15; 25-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:31; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, John Arthur, 1849-1912; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Skye, James